Eduardo Yukio Rodrigues

Game Programmer

São Paulo - Brazil

EduYukioRodrigues@gmail.com +55 (11) 99243-2748

<u>Linkedin</u>

Portfolio

Summary

Professional with more than **3 years of experience** in the mobile gaming industry, I worked on creating, updating and fixing features in more than **10 commercial games**, which together account for 150 million downloads on Android and iOS. Graduated from **USP in Computer Science**, I worked with several code bases in **Lua** and **Python**, developed dozens of personal games using **Unity** and **Godot**, and participated in 10 game jams, reaching Top 7 among 1880 games.

Skills

- Core: Unity, C#, Lua, Love2D, Python, Git, Godot.
- Additional: SQL, C, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VSCode, GoCD, ClickUp, GIMP, Audacity, Spine, Ubuntu, VirtualBox.
- Languages: Portuguese (native), English (advanced).

Professional Experience

Game Programmer - Tapps Games (Remote)

Oct 2023 - Nov 2024 (1 year, 2 months)

- Implemented 3 minigames for the *My Boo* game, as well as new themes, skins and an IAP offer for *Vlogger Go Viral!* which removes Ads and gives Rewarded Ads rewards immediately, generating thousands of dollars weekly.
- Implemented the FTUE, a minigame and many animations for the Do Not Disturb! series, including Spine adjustments.
- Developed a reusable code package to implement IAP promotional offers in multiple games.
- Created a tool from scratch, in Python, whose graphical interface was created using the *tkinter* library, automating processes, increasing productivity and giving more autonomy to the team's Game Designers and Artists.
- Managed and mentored 2 interns, promoting the development of their skills through pair programming sessions, knowledge sharing, behavioral feedback and regular code reviews.
- · Manipulated player Save file databases, with SQL, preventing problems with sensitive updates.
- · Created and changed extensions for Visual Studio Code that were acquired by hundreds of people.
- Translated business decisions into technical solutions, evaluating the feasibility of proposals, executing demands following the Kanban methodology, implementing efficient algorithms in Lua and producing stable deliveries.

Junior Game Programmer - Tapps Games (Remote)

Sep 2021 - Sep 2023 (2 years, 1 month)

- Developed gameplay features to the game *Evolution Galaxy*, including a minigame with its own interface, a comet that offers items to the player and a progress acceleration system, available via Ads and hard currency.
- Ported My Boo minigames to My Grumpy, integrating different code bases, with different standards.
- Implemented features in the game *Vlogger Go Viral!* that went through an A/B Testing process, managed through Firebase Remote Config, aimed at collecting data and ensuring the optimization of the user experience.
- Interpreted Firebase Crashlytics data, identifying bugs, crashes and critical performance issues.
- Released frequent updates for dozens of games on Google, Apple and Amazon platforms, using GoCD.
- · Created readable, scalable and easy-to-maintain codes, working in an agile environment with Scrum methodology.

Game Programming Intern - Tapps Games (São Paulo, Brazil)

May 2017 - Aug 2017 (4 months)

• Developed gameplay elements (minigames, interactive objects), systems (energy, tips, progression), screens (main, settings, shop) and several popups to the games *Match the Emoji* and *Wedding Salon Dash*, using the Lua language.

Personal Projects

Mechanical Playground - Unity/C# | 2D Action-platformer | Solo | PC | University project | Video | Code | Play! | - 2020

- Implemented finite state machines using the State design pattern, to create more than 20 game mechanics.
- Created a system in which the player can choose any combination of 6 mechanics and use them together.

Nothing Matters - Godot | 2D Puzzle-platformer | Team of 8 people | PC | Ludum Dare 45 | Video | Code | Play! | - 2019

• Developed the movement and item systems, in addition to 70+ bugfixes. Top 7 innovation, 149 overall (1880 games).

Fallen Angel - Unity/C# | 2D Vertical-scrolling shooter | Solo | PC | Ludum Dare 48

| <u>Vídeo</u> | <u>Code</u> | <u>Play!</u> | - 2021

• Made the game from scratch (programming, design, music, sfx and art) in 48h. Top 282 fun, 389 audio (1145 games).

Education

- Bachelor in Computer Science (finished)
- Bachelor in Computer Engineering (interrupted)

Universidade de São Paulo - IME

2018 - 2021

Universidade de São Paulo - Poli

2014 - 2017